# **Bradley Allen**

Port Arthur, TX 77642 (409) 365-9024

allenbradley91@hotmail.com

bradleydallen.com

# **Summary Skills**

Exceptionally driven and dependable technical problem solver with a customer service record and superb work ethic. Highly proficient in understanding technical problems and producing a clear, concise, and understandable solution.

- Excellent grasp of and experience with low-level programming languages Java, C, and C++.
- Full knowledge of web design and structure including the MERN stack and the framework implementation during web development.
- Sound familiarity with using Windows, Linux, and MacOS operating systems.

Languages: C, C++, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Shell, HTML5, CSS.

Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS, MySQL, Bash, Git, AWS.

# **Experience**

#### EDF Trading North America | SCADA Engineer | TX, Remote

| 01/2024 to Present

- Development of C/C++ programs for low-level database manipulation providing increased productivity.
- Focused on providing programming knowledge to the team, along with improving the codebase.
- Implemented custom library functions in C to allow more efficient database manipulation.
- Configured routers using various networking protocols such as DNP, Modbus, TCP/IP.
- Participated in rotational 24/7 on-call support to resolve issues and maintain software uptime.

### Amazon | Software Development Engineer Intern | CA, Remote

| 05/2023 to 07/2023

- Project based internship to develop, maintain, and learn best practices in software development.
- Developed customer based software by deploying infrastructure as code (IaC) using AWS CDK.
- Participated in the Agile development cycle, and learned and developed using Amazon Web Services.
- Solved a critical problem that improved the workflow and maintenance of production software.

#### **Portfolio Website**

| 04/2022 to 06/2022

- A personal website portfolio to showcase projects, and act as a business card.
- Implemented the MERN stack, which includes MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.
- Gained experience in different web development methodologies and practices.

## **Education**

Lamar University - Beaumont, TX | Bachelor of Science

Computer Science | 12/2023